# **Nitin Garg**

## 3D Texturing & Look-development

nitin.grg@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/nitingarg2007 https://nitingarg.pages.dev Montreal, Quebec, Canada Citizenship: Canadian

Senior Texture and Look Development Artist with extensive experience in both Animation and VFX. Specialized in creating stylized and photorealistic textures for characters, props, and environments. Skilled in shader development, workflow optimization, and team mentorship.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Texture and Look Development Artist - Cinesite | Feb 2024 - Present

Montreal, Canada Credits – Smurfs, G20

- Collaborated closely with Cinesite's Feature Animation division and developed stylized and photorealistic textures for hero vehicles and large-scale organic assets ensuring consistent quality across sequences.
- Spearheaded a key R&D initiative for previs workflows from Maya to Unreal Engine, demonstrating improvements in iteration speed and visual fidelity via real-time rendering.

#### Senior Look Development Artist - Digital Domain | Jul 2023 - Aug 2023

Montreal, Canada

Credits - The Electric State

Performed look development and shader work in Houdini within a USD pipeline, focusing on detailed robot assets for close-up shots.

#### Senior Texture and Look Development Artist - Folks VFX | Jun 2022 - Jul 2023

Montreal, Canada

Credits - Wednesday (Netflix), Titans | DC, The Creator, Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania

- Created character shaders/masks for FX-driven reveals ('Wednesday'); authored primary shaders and additional details for the hero Ant-Man character ('Ant-Man').
- Ensured visual consistency for shared hero assets on 'Ant-Man' and 'The Creator' within multi-vendor pipelines by precisely recreating shaders to match look and fidelity based on references (models, textures, renders) provided by partner studios.

#### Senior Texture Artist - DNEG | Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

Montreal, Canada

Credits - Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom, Borderlands, Moonfall

 Developed textures for diverse assets including photorealistic principal digital doubles and complex, large-scale hero environments and creatures featuring organic surfaces and gore effects.

#### Senior Texture and Look Development Artist - Mr. X Inc. | Feb 2019 - Jun 2021

Toronto, Canada

**Credits** – Foundation (Apple TV), Raised by Wolves, See Season 1, The Nevers, Messiah (Netflix), Awake (Netflix), Snake Eyes: G.I Joe Origins

- Developed comprehensive training documentation and significantly streamlined the onboarding process for new artists, reducing rampup time to production readiness.
- Contributed texturing and shading across diverse projects, handling assets ranging from large-scale environments and vehicles to complex hero props with unique material requirements.

#### Senior Surfacing Artist - Qvisten Animation | May 2018 - Nov 2018

Oslo, Norway

Credits - Captain Sabeltann and the Magic Diamond

- Contributed towards establishing the look and technical pipeline for studio's major animated feature.
- Developed the final look for the principal character and hero environments and built a reusable material library for visual consistency.
- Used Zbrush to increase modeling and texture detail for closeup assets.

#### Texture and Look Development Artist - Blur Studio | Feb 2017 - Apr 2018

Culver City, California, USA

Credits - Lawbreakers Cinematic Trailer, Far Cry 5, Honor of Kings, Love Death + Robots Season1

#### Texture and Lighting Intern - NASA Goddard - USRA | Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Savannah, Georgia, USA

Credits - ICESat-2 Earth Science Mission PSA Film

#### Surfacing Artist - DreamWorks Animation | Aug 2010 - Jul 2015

Bangalore, India

Credits – Puss in Boots, DreamWorks Dragons: Riders of Berk, Madagascar 3, Penguins of Madagascar, Madly Madagascar, Kung Fu Panda, Secrets of the Scroll, Puss in Boots: The Three Diablos

Included a brief stint coordinating tasks as acting show lead for a small team (4 artists) on the 'DreamWorks Dragons Riders of Berk' TV series.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Arts, MA - Visual Effects

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, USA - 2016

### Bachelor of Science, BS - Information & Technology

Sikkim Manipal University, India - 2014

#### Professional Diploma - Visual Effects

Gnomon School of Visual Effects, California, USA - 2009

#### **SKILLS & SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY**

#### Core Skills:

- Stylized and Photorealistic Texturing (Animation and VFX)
- Shader Network Development & Debugging
- Polygon Modeling and UV Unwrapping
- Scene Lighting and Rendering (Offline and Realtime)
- VFX and Animation Pipeline Understanding
- Workflow optimization and Documentation
- Training and Curriculum Development

#### Software Expertise:

- Texturing: Substance Painter, Mari, Photoshop, ZBrush
- Shading & Rendering: 3DS Max, Maya, Arnold, RenderMan, V-Ray, Houdini
- Real-Time: Unreal Engine
- Compositing: Nuke

#### RECOGNITION

#### The Guide Award 2005 - DreamWorks Animation

Bangalore, India

Awarded for training new hires and helping to redesign the training curriculum